This incident is the greatest scandal in the history of the Czech Police!
‫هذه الحادثة من أكبر الفضائح‬ ‫التي وقعت في تاريخ الشرطة التشيكيّة!‬
Regrettably, the three murdered men
‫للأسف قُتل ثلاثة رجال‬
had connections with the former Czechoslovakia secret police.
‫لهم صلة بشرطة "تشيكوسلوفاكيا"‬ ‫السرية السابقة.‬
I'd like to believe that
‫كم أود‬
these murders have wiped out all unsavory ties to the Prague station.
‫أن تكون جرائم القتل هذه‬ ‫قد محت كلّ روابط الفساد بقسم شرطة "براغ".‬
You are all officers of this proud Czech Police force.
‫جميعكم أفراد من شرطة "التشيك" الشريفة.‬
I expect you all to act honorably.
‫أتوقع منكم جميعًا أن تكونوا شرفاء.‬
As the new commissioner, I will work to regain people's trust.
‫بصفتي المأمور الجديد،‬ ‫فإنني سأعمل على استعادة ثقة الناس.‬
I will implement thorough reforms.
‫سأعمل على تنفيذ إصلاحات شاملة.‬
Let me introduce the five members
‫اسمحوا لي بتقديم خمسة أفراد‬
of the special task force sent here from the headquarters.
‫من فرقة العمل الخاصة‬ ‫المُرسلة إلى هنا من المقر الرئيسي.‬
I expect you to cooperate with them
‫أتوقع منكم أن تتعاونوا معهم،‬
so these atrocious crimes can be solved as quickly as possible.
‫حتى تُحل هذه الجرائم الفظيعة‬ ‫في أسرع وقت ممكن.‬
Detective Suk, I presume.
‫- أنت المحقق "سوك" على ما أفترض.‬ ‫- أجل يا سيدي.‬
As the new commissioner, I'd like to express my appreciation
‫بصفتي المأمور الجديد،‬ ‫أود أن أعبّر عن تقديري،‬
for your work on this case.
‫لما حققته من إنجاز في هذه القضية.‬
Thank you.
‫شكرًا.‬
Incidentally, what case are you working on now?
‫بالمناسبة، ما القضية التي تتولّاها الآن؟‬
The case Inspector Zeman was working on, the murder of Petrov,
‫القضية التي كُلّف بها المفتش "زيمان"،‬ ‫مقتل "بتروف"،‬
the man running the unlicensed orphanage.
‫من كان يدير ميتمًا غير مُرخّص به.‬
I see.
‫حسنًا.‬
Continue working on your investigation.
‫تابع العمل على تحقيقك.‬
Yes, sir. I'll be going then.
‫حاضر يا سيدي. اسمح لي بالانصراف.‬
Wait. There's one other thing.
‫مهلًا. ثمة أمر آخر.‬
About that tall man who's a suspect in the murder of Inspector Zeman,
‫بخصوص ذلك الرجل الطويل المشتبه به‬ ‫في جريمة قتل المفتش "زيمان"،‬
have you found out anything about him?
‫هل توصلت إلى أي شيء بشأنه؟‬
No. I haven't found anything.
‫لا. لم أجد شيئًا.‬
I see. You may go now.
‫حسنًا. يمكنك الانصراف الآن.‬
Thank you, sir.
‫شكرًا يا سيدي.‬
"Jan Suk."
‫"يان سوك".‬
"Assigned to Prague Station a year ago."
‫"عُيّن في قسم شرطة (براغ) قبل عام."‬
"Had a close relationship with Inspector Zeman since he started."
‫"كان على علاقة وثيقة بالمفتش (زيمان)‬ ‫منذ أن تولى العمل."‬
"Exposed the hidden past of both detectives Patera and Janáček."
‫"فضح الماضي الخفي‬ ‫للمحققين (باتيرا) و(ياناتشيك)."‬
"Met with Commissioner Hamrlík just before his death."
‫"قابل المأمور (هامرليك) قبل وفاته مباشرةً."‬
-Keep an eye on that man. -Yes, sir.
‫- راقبوا ذلك الرجل.‬ ‫- أمرك يا سيدي.‬
Hi.
‫مرحبًا.‬
I was pretty happy when you answered the phone
‫سعدت كثيرًا بردك على الهاتف‬
at the hotel that you said you were staying at.
‫في الفندق الذي أخبرتني بأنك ستقيم فيه.‬
Did you think you have been betrayed again?
‫أحسبت أنك تعرّضت للغدر مجددًا؟‬
Well…
‫في الواقع…‬
An orange juice.
‫عصير برتقال.‬
Mr. Grimmer, you said we should meet in a crowded place.
‫سيد "غريمر"،‬ ‫قلت إننا يجب أن نلتقي في مكان مزدحم.‬
Are you sure it's all right?
‫أمتأكد من أنه لا بأس بذلك؟‬
Is what all right?
‫ماذا تقصد؟‬
The new commissioner still suspects you in the murder of Inspector Zeman.
‫لا يزال المأمور الجديد يشتبه‬ ‫في أنك من قتلت المفتش "زيمان".‬
The former Czechoslovakia secret police are still after you too, right?
‫الشرطة السرية السابقة لـ"تشيكوسلوفاكيا"‬ ‫لا تزال تلاحقك أيضًا، صحيح؟‬
Wait. Or maybe somewhere crowded is a safe place.
‫مهلًا. قد يكون المكان المزدحم مكانًا آمنًا.‬
-There are no safe places. -What?
‫- ما من أماكن آمنة.‬ ‫- ماذا؟‬
If someone wants to get me, they can do it anywhere.
‫إن أراد أحدهم أن ينال مني،‬ ‫فسيتمكن من فعل ذلك في أي مكان.‬
For example, they could do it from that window with red curtains.
‫على سبيل المثال، بالإمكان تحقيق ذلك‬ ‫عبر تلك النافذة ذات الستائر الحمراء.‬
Mr. Grimmer, who exactly are you?
‫سيد "غريمر"، من أنت بالضبط؟‬
Just a struggling journalist.
‫مجرد صحفي مناضل.‬
What? Then why are these things happening to you?
‫ماذا؟ لم تطرأ لك تلك المصائب؟‬
It's probably because I stuck my nose in too deep.
‫لأنني على الأرجح أتعمق في تقصي الحقائق.‬
It's nothing to laugh about!
‫ما من سبب يستدعي الضحك.‬
They tried to take your life.
‫لقد حاولوا قتلك.‬
-I don't mind. -Huh?
‫- لا أمانع.‬ ‫- ماذا؟‬
I knew this might happen when I snooped around.
‫عرفت أن هذا قد يحدث عند تقصي الحقائق.‬
Presently, Suk is at a cafe in Republic Square.
‫"سوك" حاليًا في مقهى في ساحة الجمهورية.‬
Like we suspected, he's meeting that tall man.
‫إنه يقابل الرجل الطويل كما توقعنا.‬
It's Grimmer for sure.
‫إنه "غريمر" بالتأكيد.‬
Yes, sir. Should I just keep him under surveillance?
‫نعم يا سيدي. هل يجب أن أبقيه تحت المراقبة؟‬
So it happened when you were investigating Petrov
‫وقع الحادث إذًا وأنت تتحرّى عن "بتروف"،‬
who had conducted brainwashing experiments
‫الذي أجرى تجارب لغسل أدمغة‬
on children in former East Germany?
‫أطفال في "ألمانيا الشرقية" سابقًا؟‬
That's right.
‫هذا صحيح.‬
Then just before Petrov died,
‫إذًا قبل موت "بتروف" مباشرةً‬
he gave you that key to a safe deposit box?
‫أعطاك ذلك المفتاح لصندوق إيداع؟‬
Yes. He also mentioned the "origin of the monster."
‫نعم. كما أنه أشار إلى "أصل الوحش".‬
"Origin of the monster"?
‫"أصل الوحش"؟‬
I don't know what it means,
‫لا أعرف ما يعنيه هذا،‬
but a lot of people seem to want to get their hands on it.
‫لكن يبدو أن ثمة الكثيرين‬ ‫ممن يريدون الاستحواذ عليه.‬
The former secret police?
‫الشرطة السرية السابقة؟‬
And a blonde-haired woman.
‫وامرأة شقراء.‬
The children from the orphanage also told me that after Petrov was killed,
‫أخبرني أطفال الميتم أيضًا‬ ‫أن بعد مقتل "بتروف"‬
they saw a beautiful blonde-haired woman leave the building.
‫رأوا امرأة شقراء جميلة تغادر المبنى.‬
Do you know who that might be?
‫أتعرف من قد تكون؟‬
I haven't got the faintest idea.
‫ليست لديّ أدنى فكرة.‬
-Are you all right? -Huh?
‫- هل أنت على ما يُرام؟‬ ‫- ماذا؟‬
You're hiding the fact that you're meeting with me from your superiors, aren't you?
‫أنت تخفي حقيقة أنك تقابلني‬ ‫من دون علم رؤسائك، أليس كذلك؟‬
You're okay with betraying the police?
‫ألا يضايقك أن تغدر بالشرطة؟‬
It's not like I'm hiding it.
‫ليست نيتي إخفاء ذلك.‬
I'm exercising investigatory discretion.
‫أنا أمارس السرية الاستقصائية.‬
After investigating thoroughly, I'll report everything.
‫بعد أن أجري تحقيقًا شاملًا،‬ ‫سأقدّم تقريرًا بما حدث.‬
I'll be able to prove your innocence after a proper investigation.
‫سأتمكن من إثبات براءتك‬ ‫بعد أن أجري تحرّياتي.‬
What's wrong?
‫ما الخطب؟‬
Slowly look to your left.
‫انظر ببطء إلى يسارك.‬
What?
‫ماذا؟‬
The man reading a paper under a parasol to your left looks suspicious.
‫الرجل الذي يقرأ صحيفة تحت المظلة‬ ‫إلى يسارك يبدو مريبًا.‬
-He's from the secret police? -He could be.
‫- هل هو من الشرطة السرية؟‬ ‫- قد يكون كذلك.‬
Anyway, ready to go?
‫على أي حال، هل أنت مستعد للانطلاق؟‬
Go where?
‫إلى أين؟‬
You brought it, right?
‫أحضرته، أليس كذلك؟‬
The key to the safe deposit box that I gave you.
‫مفتاح صندوق الإيداع الذي أعطيته لك.‬
Yes.
‫أجل.‬
Don't you want to know the truth about this "monster"?
‫ألا تريد أن تعرف حقيقة هذا "الوحش"؟‬
I do.
‫بلى.‬
Then let's get going.
‫لنتحرّك إذًا.‬
But you may be better off not knowing.
‫لكن قد يكون من الأفضل لك ألا تعرف.‬
You're looking pretty pale.
‫تبدو شاحبًا.‬
That woman's close.
‫تلك المرأة قريبة من هنا.‬
Is something wrong?
‫هل من مشكلة؟‬
No. I must be imagining things.
‫لا، لا بد أنني توهمت رؤية أمر ما.‬
Suk's on the move.
‫"سوك" يتحرّك.‬
I'll follow.
‫سأتبعه.‬
I'm Suk from the Prague Police. I called earlier.
‫أنا "سوك" من شرطة "براغ". اتصلت سابقًا.‬
One moment, please.
‫لحظة واحدة من فضلك.‬
Thank you for waiting.
‫شكرًا لك على الانتظار.‬
Please, I'll show you the way.
‫تفضل، سأرشدك إلى هناك.‬
The safe deposit boxes are in here.
‫صناديق الإيداع هنا.‬
You may use that room to examine the contents.
‫يمكنك استخدام تلك الغرفة لفحص محتوياته.‬
Research papers and a cassette tape.
‫أوراق بحثية وشريط تسجيل.‬
I brought a tape recorder.
‫أحضرت جهاز تسجيل.‬
Are you ready? I'll play it.
‫هل أنت مستعد؟ سأشغّله.‬
Where are you?
‫أين أنت؟‬
Kinderheim 511.
‫"كيندرهايم 511".‬
That's the voice of a child.
‫إنه صوت طفل.‬
What is your name?
‫ما اسمك؟‬
My name is…
‫اسمي…‬
Johan.
‫"يوهان".‬
My name is… Johan.
‫اسمي "يوهان".‬
What's your last name?
‫ما اسم عائلتك؟‬
I'll ask you again.
‫سأسألك مجددًا.‬
My name is…
‫اسمي…‬
Otto.
‫"أوتو".‬
Hans.
‫"هانس".‬
My name is… Thomas.
‫اسمي "توماس".‬
My name is…
‫اسمي…‬
Which is your real name?
‫ما هو اسمك الحقيقي؟‬
Once upon a time, in a land far away,
‫كان يا مكان في مكان بعيد،‬
there lived a nameless monster.
‫عاش وحش بلا اسم.‬
The monster was dying to have a name.
‫كان الوحش يرغب في أن يحظى باسم باستماتة.‬
Is that some kind of story?
‫أهذه قصة ما؟‬
I was waiting for Anna.
‫كنت في انتظار "آنا".‬
Who is Anna?
‫من هي "آنا"؟‬
I was waiting for Anna…
‫كنت في انتظار "آنا"…‬
while reading a picture book.
‫بينما أقرأ كتابًا مصورًا.‬
The boy was drugged before he was questioned.
‫خُدّر الفتى قبل استجوابه.‬
Where is your father?
‫أين والدك؟‬
I don't know.
‫لا أعرف.‬
Where is your mother?
‫أين أمك؟‬
I think she's alive.
‫أعتقد أنها على قيد الحياة.‬
You're a very gifted child.
‫أنت طفل موهوب جدًا.‬
Is there anything you're afraid of?
‫أثمة ما يخيفك؟‬
What are you most afraid of?
‫ما أكثر أمر يخيفك؟‬
Let me ask a different question.
‫دعني أسألك سؤالًا مختلفًا.‬
Have you ever killed anyone?
‫أسبق أن قتلت أحدًا؟‬
Lots of people died.
‫مات الكثيرون.‬
It was like… it was just Anna and me in the world.
‫بدا الأمر كما لو كنا وحدنا في الحياة.‬
Where was that?
‫أين كان ذلك المكان؟‬
Let's go back to the other question.
‫لنعد إلى السؤال الآخر.‬
What are you most afraid of?
‫ما أكثر ما يخيفك؟‬
The monster inside me is getting bigger and bigger.
‫الوحش الذي بداخلي يتضخم أكثر فأكثر.‬
Munch-munch, chomp-chomp, gobble-gobble, gulp.
‫وأخذ يقضم ويمضغ ويبتلع.‬
The thing I am afraid of the most…
‫أكثر ما أخشاه…‬
is…
‫هو…‬
I'm feeling sick! I'm going to throw up!
‫أشعر بالغثيان! سأتقيّأ.‬
Are you all right, Mr. Grimmer?
‫هل أنت بخير يا سيد "غريمر"؟‬
Yes…
‫نعم…‬
What the heck is this tape?
‫ما هذا الشريط؟‬
Is that who the monster is?
‫أذلك هو الوحش؟‬
I don't understand it at all.
‫لا أستوعب ما قيل مطلقًا.‬
We may not understand it,
‫قد لا نفهم ما قيل،‬
but there are still people who want it more than anything else.
‫لكن لا يزال هناك من يريدونه‬ ‫أكثر من أي شيء آخر.‬
Like the former Czechoslovakia secret police.
‫كشرطة "تشيكوسلوفاكيا" السرية السابقة.‬
It doesn't matter whether we listen to some of it or all of it,
‫لا يهم ما إن كنا سمعناه بأكمله أو جزء منه،‬
there's no going back for us now.
‫إذ لن يكون لنا رجعة بعد الآن.‬
What will you do with that tape and those reports?
‫ماذا ستفعل بهذا الشريط وهذه التقارير؟‬
Put them back in the safe deposit box?
‫هل ستعيدها إلى صندوق الإيداع؟‬
No. Ordinarily, I'd leave them here as evidence.
‫لا. كنت لأتركها لكونها دليلًا‬ ‫إن كنا في ظروف عادية.‬
But you'll take them?
‫لكنك ستأخذها؟‬
Then we should leave separately.
‫يجب أن يغادر كلّ منا على حدة إذًا.‬
I'm pretty sure it's me that they're after.
‫أنا متأكد من أنهم يلاحقونني.‬
Oh, right. Tell me your phone number and home address.
‫صحيح. أخبرني برقم هاتف بيتك.‬
If we make it back safely, let's contact each other.
‫إن عدنا سالمين، لنتواصل.‬
I made it home okay.
‫عدت إلى البيت سالمًا.‬
I'm getting a bad feeling.
‫ينتابني شعور سيئ.‬
I don't have a lot of confidence in him.
‫لا أثق به كثيرًا.‬
His place is on Lanover Street, huh?
‫مسكنه في شارع "لانوفر".‬
What's this all about?
‫ما سبب ما يحدث؟‬
That's what we would like to know.
‫هذا ما نود معرفته.‬
You know who we are, right?
‫تعرف من نكون، صحيح؟‬
You're members of the special task force from headquarters.
‫أنتم أعضاء في القوات الخاصة من القيادة.‬
This is Detective Third Grade Novak and I'm Detective Third Grade Zander.
‫هذا "نوفاك"، محقق من الدرجة الثالثة‬ ‫وأنا "زاندر"، محقق من الدرجة الثالثة.‬
What are you two doing at my place?
‫ما الذي تفعلانه في بيتي؟‬
How long have you been meeting Grimmer?
‫منذ متى وأنت تلتقي بـ"غريمر"؟‬
And don't tell us you haven't.
‫ولا تقل إنك لا تلتقي به.‬
You met him earlier at a cafe in Republic Square
‫قابلته في وقت سابق‬ ‫في مقهى في ساحة الجمهورية‬
and then went to Prochazka Bank.
‫ثم ذهبتما إلى بنك "بروخاسكا".‬
You know the man in this picture, don't you?
‫تعرف من في هذه الصورة، أليس كذلك؟‬
He's Captain Karel Ranke.
‫إنه النقيب "كاريل رانك".‬
He was a big shot in the Czechoslovakia secret police who went underground.
‫كان عضوًا مهمًا في شرطة "تشيكوسلوفاكيا"‬ ‫السرية وكان يعمل سرًا.‬
I don't know that man.
‫لا أعرف ذلك الرجل.‬
We checked your bank account.
‫تحققنا من حسابك المصرفي.‬
There was a large deposit this month. What's it from?
‫ثمة مبلغ كبير قد أودع في حسابك هذا الشهر.‬ ‫من أين لك به؟‬
What?
‫ماذا؟‬
What are you talking about? I don't know about any deposit!
‫عمّ تتحدث؟ لا أعرف شيئًا عن أي وديعة!‬
Your mother is hospitalized
‫حُجزت والدتك،‬
at the Krumlov National Hospital with a serious illness, isn't she?
‫في مستشفى "كروملوف" الوطني‬ ‫لإصابتها بمرض خطير، أليس كذلك؟‬
It must cost a bundle just to cover hospital expenses.
‫لا بد أنه يلزمك الكثير من المال‬ ‫لدفع مصاريف المستشفى.‬
What are you implying?
‫إلام تلمّح؟‬
After your mother divorced your father, she raised you alone.
‫بعدما طلّقت والدتك والدك، ربّتك بمفردها.‬
You're very close to your mother, aren't you?
‫صلتك بوالدتك قوية، أليس كذلك؟‬
What are you implying?
‫إلام تلمّح؟‬
We're going to search your place.
‫سنفتش بيتك.‬
Fine, look all you like.
‫فتّشه كما تريد.‬
I'm not hiding anything!
‫أنا لا أخفي شيئًا!‬
Look all you like.
‫فتّشاه كما تريدان.‬
Zander, come here a sec.
‫"زاندر"، تعال إلى هنا لحظة.‬
What are these?
‫ما هذه؟‬
They were in a cabinet in your bathroom.
‫كانت في خزانة حمّامك.‬
I've never seen these before.
‫لم أرها من قبل.‬
We can't tell what the drug is until It's been tested at the station.
‫لا يمكننا التيقّن من نوعية المخدّر‬ ‫إلا بعد فحصه في قسم الشرطة.‬
But the muscle relaxant that killed
‫لكن مرخّي العضلات الذي قُتل به‬
the three men at the station was found in…
‫الرجال الثلاثة‬ ‫الذي كانوا في القسم عُثر عليه…‬
whiskey bonbons they ate.
‫في حلوى ويسكي تناولوها.‬
Come with us to the station.
‫رافقنا إلى قسم الشرطة.‬
Fine, I will.
‫حسنًا، سأرافقكما.‬
Question me all you like.
‫استجوبوني كما تشاؤون.‬
We will.
‫سنفعل ذلك.‬
I'm sorry,
‫أنا آسف،‬
but could I change my shirt before I go?
‫لكن هل لي أن أغيّر قميصي قبل المغادرة؟‬
Sure, that's fine.
‫بالتأكيد، لا بأس.‬
Stay calm.
‫حافظ على هدوئك.‬
I haven't done anything wrong.
‫لم أقترف أي خطأ.‬
If I explain everything, they'll understand.
‫إن وضّحت لهم ما حدث، فسيتفهمون موقفي.‬
I smell gunpowder smoke.
‫أشم رائحة بارود.‬
Suk!
‫"سوك"!‬